<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Page on Q&#39;s 🌱</title>
    <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Page on Q&#39;s 🌱</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://QWxleA.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>digital garden</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/digital-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/digital-garden/</guid>
      <description>Note: This place is currently a placeholder, hugo gets upset if links are missing.
   References    Building a digital garden
  A Brief History &amp;amp; Ethos of the Digital Garden
  Also: MaggieAppleton/digital-gardeners: Resources, links, projects, and ideas for gardeners tending their digital notes on the public interwebs
  And: (2) Maggie Appleton 🧭 on Twitter: &amp;ldquo;Nerding hard on digital gardens, personal wikis, and experimental knowledge systems with @_jonesian today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How and why to tag your Daily Notes</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/how-and-why-to-tag-your-daily-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/how-and-why-to-tag-your-daily-notes/</guid>
      <description>About resurfacing information from your Daily Notes    During the day I run into many interesting topics, tweets, posts on Reddit, thoughts from books, too many to keep track of. I keep everything that I might want to use later, some people are picky, I&amp;rsquo;m not. Not being picky means I don&amp;rsquo;t have to make any decisions right now -&amp;gt; which reduces [[friction]].
  If not tagged, the daily note becomes a black hole where information just disappears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hugo</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/hugo/</guid>
      <description>The plan is to collect useful snippets and code-examples to help creating and maintaining a pkm in Hugo (and posibly Logseq).
   Automating import  To import pages from logseq:
#!/usr/bin/env bash  BLOG=$HOME/Documents/QWxleA.github.io NOTES=$BLOG/content/notes ASSETS=&amp;#34;$BLOG/content/notes/assets&amp;#34; HUGOASSETS=$BLOG/static/assets  STARTPAGE=&amp;#34;$NOTES/Start here.md&amp;#34;  ZIP=$HOME/Downloads/publicExport.zip  explode() {  # rm $NOTES/*.md   unzip -o -d $NOTES $ZIP  if [ -d &amp;#34;$ASSETS&amp;#34; ]; then  for a in $ASSETS/*; do  mv &amp;#34;$a&amp;#34; $HUGOASSETS  done  rmdir &amp;#34;$ASSETS&amp;#34;  fi  # FIXME  if [ -f &amp;#34;$STARTPAGE&amp;#34; ]; then  mv &amp;#34;$STARTPAGE&amp;#34; &amp;#34;$BLOG/content/_index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>javascript</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/javascript/</guid>
      <description>Logseq plugins are developed in Javascript and that is the reason I have been reading more on how to use it well. Here you will find mostly notes related to plugin development.
See also [[typescript]]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>logseq</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/logseq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/logseq/</guid>
      <description>Note: This place is currently a placeholder, hugo gets upset if links are missing. In the future this page will be a collection of useful links to learn how to more effectively use Logseq.
Related: javascript for plugins, datalog for queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>query views</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/query-views/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/query-views/</guid>
      <description>Queries are build in a language called datalog, the presentation is done using Hiccup. Mixed in is Clojure, of which I know none.
   Debugging    Usually I add one of these to view raw data from a query before I add custom hiccup view
  :view (fn [result] (for [r result] [:pre (pr-str r)]))
  :view (fn [result] (pr-str result))
     Properties   #+BEGIN_QUERY {  :query [:find (pull ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>building a digital garden with Logseq and Hugo</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/building-a-digital-garden-with-logseq-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/building-a-digital-garden-with-logseq-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>We, as people, are social animals. We live together, we work together, we relax together, but what about learning together? In these days of global pandemics and, be honest, living inside our digital tools we have slowly gone back to being not-very-social. Digital gardens are one way to overcome this modern ill: Learning and building/creating in such a way that it is easy for others to see and/or comment on what you do and learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>datalog</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/datalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/datalog/</guid>
      <description>Note: This place is currently a placeholder, hugo gets upset if links are missing.
   References   Go-to links for Datalog: Learn Datalog Today! Datomic Queries and Rules | Datomic  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pkm</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/pkm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/pkm/</guid>
      <description>Personal knowledge management (PKM) is a process of collecting information that a person uses to gather, classify, store, search, retrieve and share knowledge in their  daily activities  (Grundspenkis 2007) and the way in which these processes support work activities (Wright 2005). It is a response to the idea that knowledge workers need to be responsible for their own  growth and learning  (Smedley 2009). It is a  bottom-up approach  to knowledge management (KM) (Pollard 2008).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming to a chromecast</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/streaming-to-a-chromecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/streaming-to-a-chromecast/</guid>
      <description>My mom complained about an English only TV series on Disney+. What&amp;rsquo;s a helpful son to do?
As it happens, streaming to a Chromecast is not hard, but sending subtitles to it seems to be all but impossible. So, hardcoded subs it is (Just like the nineties, how retro!).
   Step by step    This was the easiest way to get some subtitled videos on TV:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>domain-specific language</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/domain-specific-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/domain-specific-language/</guid>
      <description>A domain-specific language (DSL) is a computer language specialized to a particular application domain — Wikipedia
A &amp;ldquo;language-within-a-language&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiccup</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/hiccup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/hiccup/</guid>
      <description>Hiccup is a domain-specific language for generating HTML, used mostly in Clojure community.
For every day use you need very little knowledge of Hiccup, and fortunately (most of it) is surprisingly simple.
   Let&amp;amp;rsquo;s Hiccup   The most obvious thing you can use Hiccup for is to style the titles of Advanced Queries:  #+BEGIN_QUERY {:title [:h3 &amp;#34;This is hiccup!&amp;#34;]  :query [:find (pull ?b [*])  :where  [task ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - testpage</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/hugo-testpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/hugo-testpage/</guid>
      <description>Hugo testpage    This is a testpage, this is the kind of page you would store in Logseq, to be exported to Hugo
  This is just a second paragraph.
     This should be another headline    With some text
  And some more
     Headline 3    Lorem lipsum
  Lipsum lorum</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>daily note</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/daily-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/daily-note/</guid>
      <description>Notes    The habit of starting all writing in the daily note reduces friction and stress
  It is just easy, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to think where stuff goes. Journaling in itself reduces stress
  If I like it I can put it in more permanent place
  Play-space, solves high barrier. Prototype and just write.
    Logging progress in the daily journal creates the possibility to see progress</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>procrastination</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/procrastination/</guid>
      <description>+ **relevant notes**:   [[motivation]] [[addiction]]  definition: Procrastination is the action of  unnecessarily and voluntarily delaying  or postponing something  despite knowing that there will be negative consequences  for doing so. Oftentimes, it is a habitual human behaviour. — Procrastination - Wikipedia
Criteria: it must be counterproductive, needless, and delaying</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>time management</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/time-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/time-management/</guid>
      <description>Always been complicated. What seems to work is several pomodoros, but not more, why so few?
Major problem is procrastination, what can be done?
Different techniques:
  Time blocking
  pomodoro technique — gently kicking yourself into action
  taking a break</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Queries</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/advanced-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/advanced-queries/</guid>
      <description>Placeholder for an Advanced queries tutorial</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pomodoro</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/pomodoro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/pomodoro/</guid>
      <description>The Pomodoro Technique is a time management method developed by Francesco Cirillo in the late 1980s. It  uses a timer to break work into intervals , traditionally  25 minutes  in length, separated by short breaks. Each interval is known as a pomodoro, from the Italian word for &amp;rsquo;tomato&amp;rsquo;, after the tomato-shaped kitchen timer Cirillo used as a university student. — Pomodoro Technique - Wikipedia
Why does it work (for me)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spaced repetition</title>
      <link>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/spaced-repetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://QWxleA.github.io/page/spaced-repetition/</guid>
      <description>Spaced repetition, usually used to memorize information, can also be used as a study workflow #rephrase. How? #card #seedling
 Add #card #seedling to a particular block that you want to revisit and study further.     Linked references  Evergreen note maintenance approximates spaced repetition -&amp;gt; expand
 We learn something not only when we connect it to prior knowledge and try to understand its broader implications (elaboration), but also when we try to retrieve it at different times (spacing) in different contexts (variation), ideally with the help of chance (contextual interference) and with a deliberate effort (retrieval).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
